This video gives a brief introduction to the Arclight device.
Switch it on using this grey button.
At first, both ends of the Arclight may come on at the same time.
If it does not come on at all or the lights are dim, the battery may be flat.
Plug it in using the USB charger.
When charging, the green lights will come on.
After 15 minutes, it should be fully charged and work for several hours.
Leaving it in sunlight will keep the battery charged.
You will not need to replace any batteries or bulbs.
The mode when both ends come on is for general use.
Switch to eye mode by holding the button down for 15 seconds.
Then lift your fingers and quickly press again as the light flashes.
You are now in eye mode, where the ophthalmoscope will come on
first, then the anterior segment loupe.
Repeating these steps will cycle through three different modes of use.
General use, eyes, then ears.
Once you have selected the preferred mode, pressing the grey button
changes how bright the lights are and which end is lit.
Make sure you use the correct end for the correct examination.
The external eye is examined by using the loupe.
The view will be clear when you are very close to the eye at around 6 cm.
The fundal reflex is performed at arm's length using the direct ophthalmoscope.
If the view is blurred, then check the lens rack is at the top.
In this position, there is no lens in the sight hole and the reflex should be clear.